palness.com 2011-08-08

# Privacy Policy » Palness Social Network

**Palness Privacy Policy**

Your privacy is important to us. We will never use or share the personally identifiable information provided to us online outside the context of this Policy. To better protect your privacy we provide this notice explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. To make this notice easy to find, we make it available on our homepage and at every point where personally identifiable information may be requested.   
**  
Information Collected Upon Registration:**

When you create or reconfigure a Palness account, you provide some personal information, such as your name, address, username and email address. Some of this information, for example, your name and username, is listed publicly on our Services, including on your profile page and in search results. Some Services, such as search, public user profiles and viewing lists, do not require registration.   
**  
Additional Information: **

You may provide us with additional information to make public, such as a short biography, your location, or a picture. You may customize your account with information such as a cell phone number for the delivery of SMS messages or your address book so that we can help you find Palness users you know. We may use your contact information to send you information about our Services or to market to you. You may unsubscribe from these messages by following the instructions contained within the messages or the instructions on our web site. If you email us, we may keep your message, email address and contact information to respond to your request. Providing the additional information described in this section is entirely optional. 

**Following, Lists and other Public Information:**

Our Services are primarily designed to help you share information with the world. Most of the information you provide to us is information you are asking us to make public. This includes not only the messages you Post and the metadata provided with the post, such as when you Post on the forum or elsewhere, but also the lists you create, the people you follow, the blogs you mark as favorites or any content and many other bits of information. Our default is almost always to make the information you provide public but we generally give you settings to make the information more private if you want. Your public information is broadly and instantly disseminated. For example, your public Post are searchable by many search engines and are immediately delivered via SMS and our APIs to a wide range of users and services. You should be careful about all information that will be made public by posting or blogging, not just your profile informations. 

What you say on Palness may be viewed all around the world instantly.   
**  
Location Information:**

You may choose to note your location in your Palness profile. If you turn on your location, we may also save exact coordinates to help improve our service. You can control your location information settings in your account settings. 

**Log Data:**

Our servers automatically record information ("Log Data") created by your use of the Services. Log Data may include information such as your IP address, browser type, the referring domain, pages visited, and search terms. Other actions, such as interactions with advertisements, may also be included in Log Data. 

**Links:**

Palness may keep track of how you interact with links in palness.com by redirecting clicks or through other means. We do this to help improve our Services, including advertising, and to be able to share aggregate click statistics such as how many times a particular link was clicked on. 

**Third Party Services:**

Palness uses a variety of services hosted by third parties to help provide our Services, such as hosting our various blogs and wikis, and to help us understand the use of our Services, such as Google Analytics. These services may collect information sent by your browser as part of a web page request, such as cookies or your IP request.   
Information Sharing and Disclosure.   
**  
Log Files**   
Like many other Web sites, Palness makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol ( IP ) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider ( ISP ), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses, and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable.   
**  
Cookies and Web Beacons**   
Like many websites, we use "cookie" technology to collect additional website usage data and to improve our Services, but we do not require cookies for many parts of our Services such as searching and looking at public user profiles or lists. A cookie is a small data file that is transferred to your computer's hard disk. Palness may use both session cookies and persistent cookies to better understand how you interact with our Services, to monitor aggregate usage by our users and web traffic routing on our Services, and to improve our Services. Most Internet browsers automatically accept cookies. You can instruct your browser, by editing its options, to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the websites you visit. 

Palness does use cookies to store information about visitors preferences, record user-specific information on which pages the user access or visit, customize Web page content based on visitors browser type or other information that the visitor sends via their browser.   
**  
DoubleClick DART Cookie**   
.:: Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on Palness.   
.:: Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to Palness and other sites on the Internet.   
.:: Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL - http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html 

Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site. Our advertising partners include ....   
Google Adsense 

These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on Palness send directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies ( such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons ) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and / or to personalize the advertising content that you see. 

Palness has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers. 

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. Palness's privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites. 

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers' respective websites 

However, We do not disclose your private information except in the limited circumstances described here. 

**Your Consent:**

We may share or disclose your information with your consent, such as when you use a third party web client to access your Palness account.   
**  
Service Providers:**

We engage certain trusted third parties to perform functions and provide services to us. We may share your personal information with these third parties, but only to the extent necessary to perform these functions and provide such services, and only pursuant to obligations mirroring the protections of this privacy policy. 

Law and Harm: We may disclose your information if we believe that it is reasonably necessary to comply with a law, regulation or legal request; to protect the safety of any person; to address fraud, security or technical issues; or to protect Palness's rights or property.   
**  
Business Transfers:**

In the event that Palness is involved in a bankruptcy, merger, acquisition, reorganization or sale of assets, your information may be transfered as part of that transaction. The promises in this privacy policy will apply to your information as transferred to the new entity.   
**  
Non-Private or Non-Personal Information:**

We may share or disclose your non-private, aggregated or otherwise non-personal information, such as your public contents or the number of users who clicked on a particular link (even if only one did). 

**We will never use or share the personally identifiable information provided to us online in ways unrelated to the ones described above without also providing you an opportunity to opt-out or otherwise prohibit such unrelated uses**.   
**  
Modifying Your Personal Information**

If you are a registered user of our Services, we provide you with tools to access or modify the personal information you provided to us and associated with your account. 

**Our Policy Towards Children**

Our Services are not directed to people under 13. If you become aware that your child has provided us with personal information without your consent, please contact us at privacy@palness.com. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. If we become aware that a child under 13 has provided us with personal information, we take steps to remove such information and terminate the child's account.   
**  
Changes to this Policy**

We may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time. The most current version of the policy will govern our use of your information and will always be at http://palness.com/privacy/ If we make a change to this policy that, in our sole discretion, is material, we will notify you via an Palness update or e-mail to the email associated with your account. By continuing to access or use the Services after those changes become effective, you agree to be bound by the revised Privacy Policy. 

This Privacy Policy is effective as of September 21, 2010. 

If you have question related to your privacy, contact us through: privacy@palness.com
